pix4d.com 2017-04-16

# Privacy Policy - Pix4D

At Pix4D, we are committed to provide our users and customers meaningful privacy policy protections. Our Policy describes the methods that we use to collect, store, process and use your personal information and other data across our website and our services (including our software, our mobile apps and our web-based services). 

For your convenience, this below provides the highlights of our Policy at a glance:

  * We collect two types of personal information: 1) information such as your name, address, email, IP address, which are used to identify you and to interact with you, and 2) information on your use of our website (incl. using Google Analytics) and our services, which we use to improve our website and services and to solve technical issues. 
  * All personal information is protected against unauthorised treatment or access by appropriate technical and organisational measures. Your personal information is stored and processed on our servers in Switzerland and in the United States.
  * By making the necessary changes, you may opt-out of usage information collected by Google Analytics (see Section 8) and/or our desktop applications (see Section 5). Should you no longer wish to receive our newsletters, you may simply click the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each newsletter.
  * For more details, please refer to the full Policy below. Should you have questions, please feel free to contact us at legal@pix4d.com

We may amend this Policy from time to time to reflect changes in applicable laws or in our services. The amended Policy will take effect on the date of publishing. Your continued use of our website and/or our services after such notification of change will constitute acceptance of the amendments. You may also be asked to re-acknowledge and reaccept this Policy through our services following any material changes.

**IMPORTANT**

By providing us with personal information, by using our website, and/or by using our services, you are consenting that we collect, store, process and use your personal information as well as other data according to the applicable law and to the terms and conditions of this Policy. If you do not agree with this Policy, please do not provide us with any personal information. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with the required personal information, we may however be totally or partially unable to provide you our services.

### **What personal information do we collect?**

When you register to use our website, or contact us, we may collect information that identifies you, including your name, postal address, email address, phone number, payment information, company name, etc. When you visit our website, we may further collect information sent by your browser or device to our servers, including your IP address (which may indicate us your general location). 

### **How is my personal information used and shared?**

As a general rule, your personal information will not be used for any other purposes than those for which they were provided to us (information request, login to our website, billing, sending payment reminders, etc.). Your personal information is shared or transferred to third parties if such sharing or transfer is required to achieve the purposes for which you have transferred them to us (including but not limited to data storage, maintenance, database management, web analytics, payment processing services). We may also disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect and defend our rights or property, (iii) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the website or the public, (iv) protect against legal liability or (iv) prevent fraudulent use of or access to our website or services.

Further, we reserve our right to use all or part of your personal information for other purposes, such as to improve our website, communicate with you, conduct surveys or recommend those of our services that could be of interest to you. You may object receiving newsletter by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the newsletter email.

### **What other data do we collect?**

When you visit our website, we may collect information sent by your browser or device to our servers, including the type of browser and device you use, your usage preferences, the page that led you to our website, the key-words that you typed into a search engine that led you to our website (if applicable), etc. We collect this information using cookies or similar technologies (see Section 8). 

We may also collect and process data on your use of – and behaviour in – our software, mobile apps and web-based services, including:

  * the type of device you use and your system information (operating system, processor and amount of memory installed);
  * our product information (version number and license key);
  * the use of some of our services by authorised users;
  * your usage preferences (such as menu options or buttons selected);
  * meta-data of the images processed through our services (megapixel numbers, camera brand, focal length, project location); and
  * processing logs and statistics (camera model information, processing time and parameters, number of images, coordinate system, settings, etc.).

### **How is such data used and shared and how to opt-out?**

The data regarding your use of our services is associated with your Pix4D account and shall be used solely to personalize your experience of our services, to help our product team to improve our services, to help us diagnose and solve any technical issues with our services, to communicate with you, and in some cases for billing purposes. It will not be shared with third parties unless it is required by law or by a court order, or upon sale of our business.

You may object to the use of your data gathered through our desktop applications by disabling this function in the settings of Pix4Dmapper (opting-out). By doing so, none of the optional data will be sent, except for the necessity of license validation check. Please note that you will have to repeat this process at each software installation.

The use, sharing and your choices with regards to data collected with cookie technologies (incl. Google Analytics) are described under Section 8.

### **How is my personal information protected?**

All personal information and other data is protected against unauthorized processing with the help of appropriate technical and organizational measures. Please however be aware that no security measure can be completely effective: you share your personal information with us at your own risk. 

### **Is Personal information transferred abroad?**

Our servers are located in Switzerland and in the United States. The data protection laws in these countries may be different from, and less stringent than, those applicable in your country of residence. By accepting this Policy, you state that you have legal authority to share your personal information with us and you expressly consent to the transfer and processing of your personal information in the above countries.

### **What are cookies?**

Cookies are little files that are stored on your data storage medium and that memorize, through your browser, some configurations and data in order to exchange them with our systems. You may prevent the installation of cookies by making the necessary changes in the settings of your Internet browser; however, we draw your attention to the fact that you may no longer have access to all the functions of our website in that case.

We also use the Google Analytics tracking technology, which is based on a certain type of cookies. Google Analytics is a service of Google Inc. (“Google”). The information produced by such cookies (which includes your IP address) are sent – and stored – on servers in the United States of America. Google will use such information to analyse, for us, your use of the website, to prepare reports regarding the activity of our website and of the Internet. Google may also communicate such information to third parties to the extent required by law or if Google entrusts such third parties with the processing of the data. For further details, please consult the [Google Privacy Policy](mailto:https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) and [How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/). By using our website, you give your consent to Google processing and collecting your personal information in the manner and for the purposes described above. As mentioned-above, you may prevent the installation of cookies by adequately configuring the settings of your browser. However, we draw your attention to the fact that you may no longer have access to all the functions of our website. You may object at any time, and for the future, to the collecting or the recording of data by Google Analytics. For more details, please see [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

### **Choices, Rights of Access and Correction**

In line with the current laws on protection of personal information, you have the right to be informed, without charge, of the data that are collected about you and, if such data are inaccurate or incomplete, to correct them, to block access to them or to delete them. In order to achieve that, you may simply connect to your account and make whatever modifications are necessary in your settings. Please note that we will retain that information about you that are necessary for us to comply with our legal and business obligations and to enforce our agreements.

### **Language**

The original version of this Policy is made in the English language. In the event of any inconsistency or contradiction between the English version and any translation thereof, the English version shall prevail.

For any questions regarding this Policy, please contact Pix4D at:  
Pix4D SA, EPFL Innovation park, Building F, 1015 Lausanne, Switzerland  
E-mail: [legal@pix4d.com](mailto:legal@pix4d.com)

Version: 24 August 2016 

All rights on this Policy belong to their author. Any reproduction, without prior license, is strictly forbidden.
